NAVIS MICHAEL BEARLY J

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - REACT AND ANGULAR

+91-9840855590

□ navis.programmer@gmail.com

https://navismichaelbearly.github.io/

OVERVIEW

I am a web developer since 2006 the period during which I have worked in different environments, from start-ups to large organizations. I am a self-motivated and self-taught professional who likes to solve problems.

I merge a passion for usability and user experience with technical knowledge to create cool digital experiences. My expertise includes programming languages/frameworks and tools such as ReactJS, Angular, HTML5, CSS3, ES6, ActionScript 3, PHP Codelgniter, Express JS, jQuery, Drupal, Wordpress, MySQL, PostgreSQL and Apache server configuration and many more. I also have experience in DevOps with Tekton CI/CD and/or Open Shift Pipelines, and Jenkins. Additionally, have exposure with Grunt, Gulp, SASS, LESS, Twitter Bootstrap, and more.

SUMMARY

- Frontend development experience with React JS, Angular, Adobe Flex and done POC with Next JS
- DevOps Experience with Jenkins, OpenShift Pipelines/ Tekton CI/CD Pipelines.
- Backend development experience with PHP Code-Igniter, Ruby on Rails and Java Spring Boot
- UI / UX Design experience with various tools like Figma, Pencil 2D
- Responsive Web site development with BootStrap, HTML, CSS, JavaScript & jQuery
- Experience in developing Software as Services (SaaS) applications.
- System Programming includes Nagios System Monitoring with the Perl, shell script and python programming and windows WMI Scripts.
- Test automation with Perl Selenium
- Domain Competency with E-commerce and Healthcare domains.
- Leadership experience by managing a technical team.

AWARDS

- Acknowledged for exceptional contributions to the FORD Culture by successfully resolving a critical Jenkins issue in the DevOps CI/CD Pipeline in 2022.
- Recognized with the prestigious Verizon SPOT Award for optimizing the performance of the Verizon's FIOS Project in 2008.

CERTIFICATION

- Front-End Web Development with React The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology and offered through Coursera
- React: Creating and Hosting a Full-Stack Site (2019) LinkedIn Learning



SKILLS

Frontend

React JS Angular JavaScript HTML5

CSS3 SASS LESS jQuery Bootstrap

jQuery Adobe Flex 3 ECMA Script 4, 6,

and 7 TypeScript Figma

Backend

Ruby on Rails PHP Codelgniter Java
Wordpress MySQL Postgres MSSQL
Oracle

DevOps

Jenkins Tekton CI/CD OpenShift

Pipelines Nagios Gradle Pivotal Cloud

Foundry Shell Script Perl Python

Checkmarx SonarQube GIT Grunt

NPM Scripts

Domains

Healthcare E-Commerce Automotive

EDUCATION

- M.S. in Software Systems from Birla Institute of Technology and Science - 2013
- B.E. in Electronics & Communication from MAM College of Engineering - 2003

WORK HISTORY

V2Soft - deployed at Ford Motors | Jul 2021 - Present

Technical Lead

Angular - React – JavaScript ES6 - Java Springboot - DevOps - Jenkins - Openshift - Tekton CI/CD

- Created Angular UI Components for contextual pricing workflow and also updated supporting backend code with Spring boot to publish price-sets for the Ford cars.
- Implemented CI/CD Pipeline using OpenShift Pipeline / Tekton for four projects, which includes multiples java projects, react and angular projects, which reduced production time by 30%.
- Created SPT Widget Ford Project, which is implemented using React 17.0.2. The application is responsible to display prices for each Ford car accessories. Achieved greater user experience for the end users.
- Created and Maintained Frontend Angular Admin console with multiple roles such as Ford Admin and Dealer for consumer accessories pricing and it also serves as input for SPT Widget.

Conso4s | Dec 2020 - May 2021

Technology Lead

React Redux - HTML5 - CSS3 - JavaScript

- Developed reusable components using React 16.8.6. The application is responsible to display different properties of the NHG Client
- Created external components using Story Book, it is an opensource tool for building UI components and pages in isolation.
- Handled State Management, which is implemented using Redux, and Redux Thunk was used for the middleware communications.

Self-Employed | Feb 2019 - Dec 2020

Independent Consultant

PHP - HTML5 - CSS3 - Wordpress - JavaScript

- Created portal for the Retail products of Strings Unlimited and published through web hosting.
- Developed Workshop Management system for a Car Garage using PHP, as requested by the client. System includes new client entry and maintain the car issues.
- Managed and designed a web portal for client saaiglobalservices.com and published through web hosting.
- Managed and designed a web portal for client rajakai.com and published through web hosting.

Eli India - Healthicity.com | Sep 2016 - Jan 2019

Technical Lead

PHP Codelgniter – Ruby on Rails - MixPanel – Material UI - jQuery

- Developed and maintained Auditing Manager Saas App using PHP Code Igniter
- Developed and maintained Compliance Manager Saas App using Ruby on Rails
- Built customized PDF document with external PDF library Integrated Auditing SaaS service with MixPanel for the end user activity. Delivered enhanced user metrics, which is used to enhance the UI UX of the Auditing Manager and Compliance Manager software.

 Adhered 100% to standards and best practices around development processes, coding and peer reviews.

Madura Fashion & Lifestyle (Aditya Birla Fashion & Retail Ltd.) | Aug 2015 - Sep 2016

Lead Engineer

PHP CodeIgniter - Salesforce - HTML5 - CSS3 - JavaScript

- Module lead role for Trendin.com the official online store for MFL brands from Allen Solly, Louis Philippe, Pantaloons, People, Peter England and Vanheusen.
- Facilitated meetings with Salesforce stackholder for the Customer Relation ship management.
- Volunteered and Developed SMS and Emailing system with Spring and Hibernate, which operates through backend REST API communication by the external systems that includes ECommerce and Digital Marketing Portals resulted in cutting operational costs by 20% by avoiding 3rd party mail providers.
- Organized multiple meetings with Ecommerce Head to analyze complex requirements of Ecommerce portals and Standalone Email and SMS system.

Oracle | Mar 2012 - Aug 2015

Principal Member Technical Staff

Perl Selenium - Shell scripts - PHP

- Created automated test cases and maintained the same for Multiple areas of Oracle Enterprise Manager 12c. The Test cases were implemented using Perl Selenium
- Created Internal Portal to list the defects for each owner in the portfolio
- Implemented System installation automation using Shell Script,
 Perl and Python for the Oracle Fusion Middleware

Verizon | Jul 2007 - Mar 2012

Senior Analyst

Adobe Flex 3 - Nagios - PHP - ActionScript - JavaScript

- Created AdHoc Reporting tool for Server Monitoring, which is a dashboard system for CPU memory utilization. This tool is created using Adobe Flex 3 which is based on Action Script 3 and ECMA Script 4 scripts.
- Created Monthly Reporting Utilization System for CPU and Memory based on Company Team Portfolios. The system is created using PHP, MySQL and PHP Smarty
- Created multiple components for the Work Request System, which includes AJAX dropdown and other development activities
- Automated, monitored and maintained the remote Servers of various platform using Nagios with perl and shell scripts, which cuts down operational costs by 10%.

CompIndia Infotech Pvt Ltd | Nov 2006 - Jul 2007

PHP Developer

PHP - Smarty template - HTML - CSS - JavaScript

 Created PHP/MySQL based Web system for the Car Insurance System for a company's client. Created PDF files with PHP library, it was used to create the dynamic PDF Files for Insurance documents with proper alignments.